A Guide to the Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Records, 1988-2005 (bulk 2000-2005)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Records, 1988-2005 (bulk 2000-2005)
The Library of Virginia
42293
18.15 cu. ft., 19 boxes
Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Trade
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Some Constituent Correspondence have sealed confidential records based on Codes of Virginia, 2.2-3801 and 18.2-186.3
Acquisition Information
Transferred from Secretary of Commerce and Trade by Elaine Wittel.
Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties, compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governors top management team or "secretariats," as they are called now. The General Assembly in 1972 created six Secretariats positions initially. As government reorganized, that number fluctuated when government agencies expanded or consolidated.
The office of the Secretary of Commerce and Resources was established in 1972 and was responsible for the areas of economic development and natural resources. In 1986 this secretariat was dissolved and split into two separate offices, the Secretary of Economic Development and the Secretary of Natural Resources. In 1993 the name of the office was changed from the Secretary of Economic Development to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade.
Past secretaries include: Maurice B. Rowe, 1972-1974; Earl J. Shiflet, 1974-1978; Maurice B. Rowe, 1978-1982; Betty J. Diener, 1982-1986; Richard M. Bagley, 1986-1988; Curry A. Roberts, 1988-1990; Lawrence H. Framme III, 1990-1992; Cathleen A. Magennis, 1992-1994; Robert T. Skunda, 1994-1998; Robert J. Stolle, 1998; and Barry E. DuVal, 1998-2002.
The Secretary of Commerce and Trade is appointed by the governor and serves as a member of his cabinet. The Secretary of Commerce and Trade's chief responsibility is to manage the direction of several state agencies that are concerned with the development of commerce and economic development throughout the Commonwealth. Some of the agencies reporting to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade include: Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services; Department of Economic Development; Department of Labor and Industry; Department of Mines, Minerals, and Energy; Virginia Employment Commission; Virginia Housing Development Authority; Department of Professional and Occupational Regulations; Department of Housing and Community Development; Milk Commission; Department of Minority Business Enterprise; Department of Forestry; Virginia Port Authority; Virginia Racing Commission; and Virginia Resource Authority.
Scope and Content
This collection contains memorandums, correspondence, and reports documenting the administration, management and direction of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Constituent Correspondence, 1988-2005 (bulk 2002-2003)
Series II. Special Projects-Company Files VEDP, 2001-2003
Series III. General Correspondence, 2000-2004
Series IV. Company Files, 1994-2001
Contents List
- Series I. Constituent Correspondence, 1988-2005 (bulk 2002-2003)., Extent: 12 cu. ft. (Box 1-12)
  The Constituent Correspondence provide the citizens concerns and the efforts of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade to carry out the vision of the Warner administration to increase commerce and trade development in the Commonwealth. The letters cover a variety of topics over the four year time frame. One of the main topics of interest that resulted in many letters to the Secretary include the proposed introduction of Senate Bill 260 animal cruelty legislation requiring rule changes for the definition of an animal shelter. The new definition would have required animal foster homes be included in the definition of "animal shelters" and place limits on the number of animals that can be allowed in a foster home. The bill would have also require a fee payment for each foster care animal.
  There are many request for extension of unemployment claim benefits to citizens of the Commonwealth impacted by the economic downturn from the attack on September 11, 1999. The correspondence also reflect people writing to the Governor requesting assistance with other unemployment claim problems and the Governor's office transferring those request to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade.
  The series provides copies of proclamations issued to counties suffering due to drought conditions and resulting in receiving federal aid for the troubled communities. Price gouging complaints by citizens that happened during and after Hurricane Isabel involving charges for commodities and clean up services.
  This series is arranged chronologically by constituent correspondence number.
  - 200104-200402, 2001 Dec; 2002 Jan-Mar. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 200458-200839, 2001 Feb; 2002 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 2000090-2001910, 2001 Dec; 2002 Jan-Mar. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2002008-2002982, 2001 Dec; 2002 Jan-Mar. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 2003033-2003613, 2002 Jan-Feb. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2003614-2003990, 2002 Jan-Mar; May. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 2004073-2004948, 2002 Jan; Apr-May. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 2005069-2005911, 1999 July; 2002 Jan-Apr; Sept. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 2005362; 2006117, Legal Folder 2001 Jan; June;Sept-Dec; 2002 Mar; Oct. (Box 1A, Folder 1)
  - 2006001-2006300, 2002 Feb-Mar; May. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 2007323-2008276, 2002 Feb-April; July. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 2008360-2009930, 2000 July-Aug; 2001, Sept-Nov; 2002, Jan-Apr. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 2010395-2011971, 2001 Feb; Dec; 2002, Jan-Mar, May. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 2011975-2012943, 2002 Mar-May. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 2013063-2013638, 2002 Feb-May. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 2013669-2013885, 2002 Jan-May. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 2014007-2014521, 2002 Mar-Apr. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 2014524-2014945, 1999 Feb; 2002 Jan; Mar-Apr. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 2015016-2015956, 2002 Mar-May. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 2016089-2016149, 2002,Mar-Apr. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 2016243-2016996, 2002, Feb; Mar-June. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 2017010-2018377, 2002, Mar-June. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 2018529-2018949, 1995 June; 2000 Jan; May; July; 2001 Oct; 2002 Mar-May; Sept. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 2019100-2019566, 1999 Dec; 2000 Apr-May. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 2020007-2020942, 2002, Feb; May. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 2021016-2021819, 2002, Feb; Apr-May. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 2022213-2022675, 2002, Apr-May. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 2023223-2023660, 2002, Apr-June. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 2023661-2023990, 2002, May-June. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 2024035-2024921, 2002, Apr-May; June-Sept. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 2025099-2025914, 2002 May-June; Sept-Oct. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 2026018-2026978, 2002 Apr-July. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 2027004-2027569, 2002 Jan; May-July. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 2028183-2030601, 2002 May-July. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 2030621-2030932, 2002 May-July. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 2031010-2031502, 2002 May-July. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 2031509-2031965, 2002 June-July. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 2032027-2032547, 2002 June-July. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 2032555-2032953, 2002 June-July. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 2033003-2033337, 2002 Mar; Apr-June; July; Aug. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 2033351-2033984, 2002 June-July; Aug. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 2034029-2034977, 2002 Apr; June-July; Aug; Oct. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 2035006-2035437, 1988 Apr July; 1991 Sept; 1994 Dec; 2002 June-July. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 2035478-2035781, 2002 Mar; Apr; July-Aug. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 2035784-2036584, 2002 July-Aug. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 2036612-2036914, 2002 June; July-Aug. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 2037012-2037945, 2002 June; July; Aug. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 2038012-2038996, 2002 May; June; July-Aug. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 2039173-2039942, 2002 July; Aug; Sept. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 2040013-2040997, 2002 July; Aug-Sept; Oct. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 2041020-2041850, 2002 June; Aug-Sept; Oct. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 2042132-2042552, 2002 Feb; Aug-Sept; Oct. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 2042554-2042933, 2002 Aug-Sept; Oct. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 2043043-2043991, 2002 Aug; Sept-Oct. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 2044019-2044915, 2002 Sept; Oct. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 2045125-2049067, 2002 July; Sept-Oct, Nov. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 2049070-2049988, 2002 Feb; Aug; Sept-Oct. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 2050166-2053918, 2002 May; Sept-Oct. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 2054017-2056472, 2002 June; Aug: Sept-Oct; Nov. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 2056492-2057873, 2002 Sept; Oct-Nov. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 2058068-2058970, 2002 Oct-Nov. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 2059045-2060897, 2002 Sept; Oct-Nov; Dec. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 2061128-2063708, 2002 Oct-Nov. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 2064032-2066925, 2002 July; Oct; Nov-Dec; 2003 Jan; Feb. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 2067171-2067924, 2002 Sept; Oct-Dec; 2003 Jan; Feb. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 2068076-2069919, 2002 Nov- Dec; 2003 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 2070100-2073409, 2002 Oct; Nov-Dec; 2003 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 2074120-2077563, 2001 Aug; 2002 Dec; 2003 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 2078000-2080790, 2002 Dec; 2003 Jan-Feb. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 2080841-2083343, 2002 Dec; 2003 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 2083378-2087499, 2003 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 2088033-2090756, 2003 Jan; Feb-Mar. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 2091113-2091952, 2003 Jan-Feb. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 2092048-2096661, 2003 Jan-Feb. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 2096793-2099798, 2003 Jan; Feb-Mar. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 2100428-2104438, 2003 Jan; Feb-Mar; Apr. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 2106115-2107823, 2002 Oct Dec; 2003 Jan; Feb-Mar; Apr. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 2108007-2109841, 2003 Jan; Feb-Mar. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 2110041-2111946, 2003 Jan; Feb-Mar. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 2112005-211568, 2003 Feb-Mar. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 2116419-2117986, 2003 Feb-Mar; Apr. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 2118081-2121389, 2002 Jan 2003 Feb-Mar; Apr. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 2121443-2124990, 2003 Feb; Mar-Apr. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 2125000-2127316, 2003 Mar-Apr. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 2127603-2130932, 2003 Mar-Apr. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 2131182-2133902, 2003 Mar-Apr. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 2134008-2137906, 2002 Dec; 2003 Mar-Apr. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 2138367-2140913, 2003 Apr- May. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 2141187-2144602, 2003 Mar; Apr-May. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 2151293-2152989, 2003 May-June; July. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 2153026-2154999, 2003 Apr-May; June. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 2155009-2156973, 2003 Apr-May; June. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 2157231-2158491, 2003 May-June; July. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 2145106-2145986, 2003 Apr-May. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 2146339-2146998, 1994 Dec; 2003 Apr- May. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 2147000-2148985, 2003 Apr- May. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 2149746-2150806, 2003 Apr-May; June. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 2159009-2159664, 2003 Apr-May; June; Sept. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 2159672-2159888, 2003 June. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 2160008-2162523, 2003 May- June. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 2162596-2164321, 2003 May- June (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 2164322-2166806, 2003 Mar-Apr June. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 2167270-2168919, 2003 June-July. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 2169104-2170733, 2003 June- July. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 2171010-2172323, 2003 June- July. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 2172341-2174998, 2003 June- July. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 2175015-2176613, 2003 June-July; Aug. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 2177115-2178999, 2003 Apr-July. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 2179156-2181578, 2003 June-July Aug. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 2181614-2184750, 2003 June-July; Aug. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 2185178-2187873, 2003 June-Aug. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 2188181-2189954, 2001-2003 July- Sept. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 2190014-2191972, 2003 July-Aug. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 2192020-2193953, 2003 July-Aug. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 2194255-2196997, 2003 Aug-Sept; Oct. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 2197002-2197972, 2003 July-Sept; Oct. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 2198159-2199956, 2003 June-Sept; Oct. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 2200049-2201935, 2003 Aug-Oct Nov. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 2202037-2205804, 2003 Sept-Oct. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 2205813-2208154, 2003 Sept-Nov; 2004 Jan. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 2208160-2212981, 2003 Sept-Oct; Nov. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 2213062-2214958, 2003 Sept- Nov. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 2215038-2216163, 2003 Sept-Nov; 2004 Jan. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 2216179-2218902, 2003 Oct-Nov; 2004 Jan. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 2219221-2220780, 2003 Oct-Dec. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 2221599-2224976, 2003 Oct-Dec. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 2225255-2228787, 2003 Oct-Dec. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 2228809-2230809, 2003 Sept-Dec. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 2231217-2234903, 2003 Oct-Dec. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 2235260-2236714, 2003 Nov-Dec. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 2236737-2238916, 2003 Nov-Dec; 2004 Jan. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 2239035-2242865, 2003 Nov-Dec; 2004 Jan. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 2243502-2247920, 2003 Oct-Dec; 2004 Jan. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 2248286-2253942, 2003 Dec; 2004 Jan-Feb. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 2254007-2256332, 2003 Dec; 2004 Jan-June. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 2256348-2259924, 2004 Jan-Apr. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 2260524-2264850, 2003 Oct; 2004 Feb-Mar. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 2265423-2269971, 2004 Feb-Mar. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 2270469-2276509, 2003 Oct; 2004 Feb-Mar. Apr (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 2277141-2283352, 2004 Mar. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 2283419-2288874, 2003 Aug; 2004 Mar-May. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - 2289044-2293742, 2004 Mar-June; Aug. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 2294118-2299980, 2004 Apr-June; July. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 2300888-2307849, 2004 Apr-July. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 2307869-2309857, 2004 Apr-July. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 2323020-2325526, 2004 June-July. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 2326713-2327943, 2004 June- July. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 2309929-2313581, 2004 Apr-July. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 2315054-2320030, 2004 Apr-July. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 2320081-2323019, 2004 June-July. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 2328039-2331283, 2004 June-July. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 2331304-2336302, 2004 June-Aug. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 2336305-2337905, 2004 June-Sept. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - 2338048-2340816, 2004 July-Sept. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - 2341104-2343003, 2004 July-Aug. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - 2343005-2344542, 2004 July-Aug. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - 2345223-2347486, 2004 Aug-Oct. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 2347503-2349374, 2004 Aug-Sept. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 2349379-2351787, 2004 Aug-Oct. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 2351804-2355949, 2004 Feb-Oct. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 2356062-2358025, 2004 Aug-Oct. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 2358181-2359660, 2004 Sept-Nov. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 2360056-2364735, 2004 Sept-Nov. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 2365117-2369912, 2004 Sept-Nov. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 2370024-2374900, 2004 Oct-Nov. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 2375319-2379662, 2004 Oct-Dec; 2005 Jan-Feb. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 2381072-2383948, 2004 Oct; Nov-Dec; 2005 Jan. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 2384050-2385419, 2004 Oct; Nov-Dec; 2005 Jan. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 2385462-2387631, 2004 Nov-Dec; 2005 Jan. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 2388203-2392656, 2004 Dec; 2005 Jan-Feb. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 2393157-2396923, 2004 Sept; Dec; 2005 Jan-Feb. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 2397070-2401043, 2005 Jan-Feb. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 2401063-2403789, 2005 Jan-Feb. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 22404433-2409979, 2004 Nov; 2005 Jan-Mar. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 2410138-2417905, 2004 Apr; 2005 Jan; Mar. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - 2418065-2423977, 2005 Jan-Apr. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - 2424099-2434933, 2005 Jan-Apr. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 2434945-2439934, 2003 Aug; 2005 Mar-Apr. (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Series II. Special Projects-Prospective Company Files VEDP, 1994-2002, (bulk 2001-2002)., Extent: 1 cu. ft. (Box 1)
  This series provides correspondence with prospective companies and organizations interested in participating in the Virginia Economic Development Partnership program. The records detail plans, concerns and questions regarding the feasibility of government fund investments in special projects/events and companies. The Aviation World's Fair highlights concerns with the success and cost of this project and features correspondence with Virginia's representatives, Mayors, and County Supervisors on success of such an enterprise. There is documentation on the cost of various state officials travels to France to study the Paris France Air show.
  There is documentation of the administrations efforts to obtain the 2012 Olympics for Washington D.C. There is correspondence between the Secretary Michael J. Schewel and leaders of the business community and Governor Mark Warner's highlighting efforts to secure the Olympics for the District. There are discussions of costs, bid proposals and the overall impact to the entire community.
  There is a complete record for the memorandum of agreement and understanding between the Commonwealth of Virginia and Volvo-GM Heavy Truck Corporation to create jobs in the state of Virginia. This agreement dates back to Governor George Allen's administration and outlines the various relationship changes based on economic conditions. The agreement stipulated certain conditions must be met in order for the company to receive state funding, subsequent layoff announcements presented a problem for the Commonwealth and Pulaski County, the home of the Volvo-GM factory.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by company or special event.
  - Aviation World's Fair Correspondence, 2001-2002. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Aviation World's Fair Memorandum of Agreement, 2000-2002. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Aviation World's Fair Paris Air Show Financial Information, 2001. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Aviation World's Fair Status Report Economic, 2002. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Aviation World's Fair Vision, 2002-2003. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Barboursville Mining Constituent Correspondence, 2002. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Barboursville Mining General Shale Products, 2002. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Barboursville Mining-Newsclippings, 2002. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Barboursville Mining-Newsclippings, 2002. (Box 13, Folder 8A (Legal Folder))
  - Barboursville Mining- Friends of Barboursville, 2002. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Microelectronics Consortium, 1999-2000. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Olympic 2012, 2002. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Olympic 2012, 2001-2002. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Olympic 2012, 2002. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Bid-Process, 2001-2002. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Candidate City Agreement, 1998-2000. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Connecting Communities Hosting History-Executive Summary, 2000. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Greater Washington Exploratory Committee, 1998. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Hosting 2004 U.S. Olympic Team Trials, 2001. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Information Packet, 2001-2002. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Media, 2000-2002. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition-Board of Directors, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition-Board of Directors, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition-Court Case, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition-Economic Impact of Hosting 2012 Olympic Games, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Fund Raising Booklet, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 General Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Government Affairs Committee, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition Information Booklet, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition Strategic Plan, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Short Pump Town Center Community Development Authority, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Software Factory, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Virginia Advanced Shipbuilding and Carrier Integration Center, 2000-2001 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Virginia Conference on World Trade (46th), 1994 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Virginia River Country, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Volvo-GM, 1995-2000 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Volvo-GM, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Volvo-GM, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Volvo-GM, Part II., 1994 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - World Congress on Information Technology, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - World Congress on Information Technology, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 40)
- Series III. General Correspondence,, 2002-2003., Extent: 1 cu. ft. (Box 1)
  This series provides the incoming and outgoing general correspondence, memorandum, and working notes of Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Michael J. Schewel. The correspondence features thank you letters to the Secretary for his work on bringing new jobs to local communities and cities of the Commonwealth by using the Governor's Opportunity Fund. There are thank you letters from the Secretary to industry leaders for working cooperatively with the Secretary. There are congratulatory correspondence from members of the business community on the selection of Michael Schewel as Secretary of Commerce and Trade. There are correspondence between Secretary Schewel and members of the General Assembly regarding progress of various projects implemented by the Secretary.
  This series is arranged chronologically by date.
  - General Correspondence, 2002 Jan-Feb. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 2002 Mar-Apr. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 2002 May. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 2002 June-July. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 2002 Aug. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 2002 Sept. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 2002 Oct. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 2002 Nov. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 2002 Dec. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 Jan-Feb. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 Mar-Apr. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 May. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 June. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 July. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 July. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 Aug. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 Sept-Oct. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 Nov-Dec. (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Series IV. Company Files,, 1994-2001., Extent: .70 cu. ft. (Box 2)
  This series offers information on companies and prospective companies committing to establishing their businesses in the Commonwealth. There are correspondence and memorandums that provide some of previous Governor James Gilmore and his staff's contacts and Governor Mark Warner's staff with these prospective companies. The actual company name involved in transactions with the Commonwealth may not be given in the title of each file due to the apparent sensitive negotiations with companies regarding possible tax benefits and or funds transferred for the purpose of having their business operations move to and employ citizens of Virginia.
  The records also reflect the historical background of companies, capital health and investments amounts and benefits that are obtained by having the businesses relocation to the Commonwealth.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - BTM Inc., (Browning Transport Management Inc.), 1998-2002. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Cadence,1999. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Cardinal Glass (Frederick County),1998. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Dupont,1999-2001. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Ericsson G.E. (Lynchburg),1994-2000. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Motorola,1997-2001. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Walmart (James City),1998-2000. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - West Creek,1994-1998. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Westvaco,1998-2000. (Box 15, Folder 9)